# Francesca Dreith

Portland, OR 97206 | 303-870-3116 | francesca.dreith@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/fdreith | blog url: https://fdreith.github.io/ | Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/francescadreith

#### JOB TITLE

Full stack engineer transitioning from a technical and creative background in product marketing and business operations into the field of web development. My experience has given me a comprehensive understanding of business operations and the ability to find innovative solutions to increase efficiency in various business systems, which lead to my interest in software development. Dedicated and adaptive employee with strong skills in communication and an excitement for new challenges.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby, Rails, SQL, Javascript, React, HTML, CSS, Microsoft Office, Social Media Marketing, Email Marketing, and experience with Illustrator and InDesign.

### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## Task Assign - <a href="https://github.com/fdreith/react-project-frontend">https://github.com/fdreith/react-project-frontend</a> | <a href="Demo">Demo</a>

Task management system for teams. Ability to assign tasks to other team members, comment on tasks, and track their progress.

- Developed using React, Redux, HTML, and CSS for the frontend, with a Ruby on Rails backend.
- Implemented user sign in with Bcrypt.

## Mindful Journal - https://github.com/fdreith/javascript-api-project | Demo

A digital journal to help maintain a writing goal with prompts based on a particular mood, and a timer to help the user stay on task. The user can look back at past entries by mood.

- Developed HTML, CSS, and Javascript frontend with a Rails API backend, with AJAX handled interactions between client and the server, and used JSON as the communication format.
- Optimizing code by using Object Oriented Javascript classes to compartmentalize code.
- Implemented serializers to streamline code, minimize AJAX calls, and display clean data within the relationships of the models.

# Book Club - https://github.com/fdreith/rails-project | Demo

A digital book club for users to track books they have read or would like to read, and have discussions surrounding a particular book.

- Built on MVC framework with Ruby on Rails, utilizing a CSS library and SQLite.
- Designed validations for user input and class level activerecord chainable scope methods for search abilities.
- Implemented Devise for User Authentication and Omniauth for third party Authentication with Google.
- Utilized appropriate restful URLs & helper methods for efficient code.

### Critter Sitter - https://github.com/fdreith/sinatra project | Demo

Communication and tracking tool for households with multiple people caring for a pet, including family, roommates, pet sitters or dog walkers.

- Designed a Content Management System (CMS) with full CRUD functionality, and Model-View-Controller (MVC) framework using ActiveRecord and Sinatra.
- Employed password hashing with Bcrypt for user sign in, and validations for uniqueness for user email.
- Developed validations for uniqueness for user input, and displays validation failures to user with error messages.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Splor TravelFort Collins, COInternship6/29/2020 - 8/4/2020

- Stack: React, Typescript, Apollo, Docker, and Hasura.
- Implementing new features and fixing bugs.
- Developing integration testing on CRA using enzyme.

**Funkwerks, LLC**Operations Coordinator

Fort Collins, CO

12/2012 - 10/2019

- Grew overall online participation by 62% by launching structured social media campaigns to increase engagement and email marketing campaigns to increase online sales by 564%, and in store sales by 84%.
- Increased employee satisfaction by increasing health benefits by 80% and implemented creative ways to maintain

team cohesiveness and company culture by hosting company events within a strict budget.

- Directed the marketing, licensing, and compliance of 12 new sales territory launches that grew sales by 24%.
- Reduced the cost of packaging materials by 29% by evaluating the price and terms from dozens of vendors.

## **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School
Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, and React program

New York City, New York 12/2019 - 05/2020

Colorado State University
Bachelor of Science (BS) in Psychology

Fort Collins, CO 12/ 2011